Welcome to this exercise task about object
diagrams. It is about the relation between
class diagrams and object diagrams. So,
above, we have been given two class diagrams
and five object diagrams below. And
we shall say for each of those whether
the object diagrams fit the class diagram. So, for
each combination of the class diagram and object
diagram, we shall indicate whether it is true
that the object diagram fits the class diagram.
Let's continue with the first object diagram
and compare it to the first class diagram.
So, is this object diagram an instance for this
class diagram? Therefore, we have to look at
the required edges here. When we look at the class
diagram, we see that C requires a D. We have got a
C object here. But there is no D object. There is
also no inheritance. No class inherits from D. So,
this cannot actually be an instance of the
first class diagram. So, I'd indicate it by
matching it with the first and then with the
second. So, this does not match with the first
class diagram. Let's continue
with the second class diagram.
Does this object diagram fit this class
diagram? Again, we have an A, and we have a C
here. So, we may look at the edges that are
required here. And we see that the C fits
because there are no requirements for B and D in
this case. And there's an edge between A and C,
which is fine as well because A's inherit
from B's and thus inherit this edge here
to Cs. So, this edge between A and C is fine. But
then there is a missing edge to Ds because of this
two here. We require two edges to the objects in
the object diagram. But we don't have them here.
So, it's not an instance of the second diagram as
well. Then maybe the second object diagram fits.
So, we check it for the first class
again. We check for the B. The B object in
the class diagram. And it has a relation to C
here. And when we look at the class diagram,
there is no relationship between B and C.
There is one between A and C. And there's
one between D and C. But B does not
inherit from one of those classes.
So, it does not fit. This edge here is problematic
for the first class diagram. So, it does not fit.
And then, we have the next class diagram.
We can also check the other constraints
of their world. C and D require one
object each. And they are connected by
this relationship here. So, this is fulfilled.
So, C has a D, and D has a C. And we may see
also that B has a connection to D, which is
optional here. But it is in the class diagram,
which is fine. But as I said before, this edge
here is problematic but not in the class diagram.
So, this would be fine if this edge were
missing. Then let's see. What about the
second class diagram? So, here we have an
edge between B and C, which is optional.
So, this edge is fine in this object diagram
considering this class diagram. We have an edge
between C and D, which is optional. And that's
fine as well. And then we have this edge between
B and D, which is here as well. But we require
two Ds for every B. We have got a single one
only. And there is no inheritance as well from D.
So, this would be the only option. So, this is not
an instance for the second class diagram as well.
Now consider the third object diagram. And here,
we have got four objects in the object diagram,
A, B, C, and D. Maybe you're stumbling about
what's happening here with the A object, which
has no name. Well, this is an anonymous object,
which is possible in the object diagram as well.
So, objects do not require to have a name. In this
case, it is an anonymous object. So, now, we have
an edge between A and C, which is okay. Because
this optional edge is fulfilled. Also, this
B and D edge is okay because it's optional.
And A's could also be connected to Ds. It's not
the case in this object diagram. But it's fine
because this inherited edge is optional. Then
we have the connection between C and D. This
relationship says every C needs a connection
to D. And every D needs a connection to C. We
have a connection from a C to a D, and we have
a connection from a D to a C. And that's exactly
one. So, we are fine for the first class diagram.
And this one matches the first class diagram.
How about the second class diagram? In this case,
we can again check. We have an edge between A and
C. And this is already problematic because there
is no connection between A and C. Is it? There is
an edge because A inherits from B. So, there is
an edge between A and C. Then this edge is fine.
Considering the edge between C and D. This is
fine as well because there is this optional
relationship. So, we have this connection as
well. Again, there is this connection between
B and C, which is optional. So here, there
is no connection. That's fine as well.
And then, we have the connection between B and
D, which is required. And B requires to have
two connections to D objects. In this case, it's
a single one. Because this two is fixed here,
it is required to have two connections. Thus,
it cannot be an instance of the class diagram.
Let's check the next object diagram. First,
again with the first class diagram. So,
we have a connection from A to C, which
is optional and fine here. We have the
required connection between C and D.
C has exactly one connection to D as
well as D exactly one to C. So, this is
fine. And we have a connection between
A and D. This connection is fine as well because
A inherits from B. Thus, it also inherits the
connection to D. So, our A is also a B. That's
why it can have a connection to D. That is fine.
And there are no further connections,
but there are also no further connections
required in our class diagram. So, this
one is valid for the first class diagram.
How about the second class diagram? In this case,
we can check again for our classes. First of all,
for our objects, let's take A and consider the
connection to a C, which is fine as it is
inherited from B. So, we have this connection
to C. Then we have an inherited connection to D.
So, A requires a connection to D via inheritance
from B. We have a connection. But again, we require
to have two connections to D, which we do not
have. So, that's why this class does not match.
But it would be fine with this C and D
connection. As this optional connection
is in the object diagram. But again, this two
once more leads to this object diagram not being
a valid instance for the second class diagram.
Now we have to consider the last object diagram.
First of all, again, for the first class diagram.
So, now we have a connection to two Ds within our
object diagram. And if we check the class diagram,
we see that A inherits from B. Thus, it can have a
connection to D. It can have several connections.
So, it's totally fine because of this aggregation
here. It's totally fine to have also two
connections to D objects. But our D objects
require a connection to a C object. And this is
not the case in the object diagram. So, there is
no connection to any C for either of those Ds.
So, it does not fit the first class diagram.
Now, we can check for the second class diagram.
Once more, we inherit the connections from B
when we have an A object. And so, this A object may
be connected to a C object. It is not. But that's
fine as well because this is optional. And we can
check for connections to D. So, we require two D
objects for each B object. And because of the
inheritance, it's also required for each A object. So,
this A object is connected to two D objects.
Thus, this is totally fine. This relationship
between C and D is optional. And that is why this
object diagram does fit the second class diagram.
And then we are done with this task. And we
have to simply write the reasons why it is
not an instance if the object diagram is
not an instance on all the X cases. If
you've written what I have said more
or less, or at least the reasons for
which the object diagram cannot be an
instance, then you've fulfilled the task.